<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-09T01:09:51-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ethan Ding</title><subtitle>Ethan Ding's project website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Xenon Ventures Internship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/xenon-ventures-internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xenon Ventures Internship" /><published>2019-06-04T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-04T12:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/xenon-ventures-internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/xenon-ventures-internship/">&lt;p&gt;What a day, I’m flying into Japan to meet Jonathan Siegel, the legend himself in the flesh. I’m probably hyping this up too much, but fuck me if I’m not excited. Most the offer letters felt really strange to me: these were companies that valued prim-and-proper, by the book decision making. They crafted narratives online how they were diverse workplaces that cared about hiring unique individuals who thought outside the box, but I never felt any… spirit or charisma come out of interacting with Deloitte consultants or Goldman bankers. They seemed caught up in their own world of semantics, probable office politics, maintaining shallow and facetious relationships that ultimately ring hollow. They call it professionalism and it feels stifling to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents want me to start recruiting for these companies since the process has started. I don’t know how I feel about it. Everything I am, everything I do, is crafted around being the most genuine person I can be, even if it might momentarily put tension into the relationships I am building, I would rather there be tension in a genuine and transparent interaction than present a side of myself I don’t like seeing in the mirror when I wake up. BlackRock, Deloitte, D.E. Shaw, Citadel, all these places I find myself hesitant about working at on account of the possibly endlessly bureaucratic systems feel like places where I might end up losing who I am.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Internship" /><category term="Private Equity" /><summary type="html">What a day, I’m flying into Japan to meet Jonathan Siegel, the legend himself in the flesh. I’m probably hyping this up too much, but fuck me if I’m not excited. Most the offer letters felt really strange to me: these were companies that valued prim-and-proper, by the book decision making. They crafted narratives online how they were diverse workplaces that cared about hiring unique individuals who thought outside the box, but I never felt any… spirit or charisma come out of interacting with Deloitte consultants or Goldman bankers. They seemed caught up in their own world of semantics, probable office politics, maintaining shallow and facetious relationships that ultimately ring hollow. They call it professionalism and it feels stifling to me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/google.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Tech Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-tech-challenge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Tech Challenge" /><published>2019-04-25T07:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-25T07:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-tech-challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-tech-challenge/">&lt;p&gt;25 April&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Tech Challenge wasn’t quite what I expected. I expected a series of diverse challenges across a simultaneously physical and mental obstacle course that centred around olympiad type mathematics. It was not that, instead I found myself surrounded by Computer Science and EECS students from Berkeley and Stanford, competing in coding problems to see who can solve them the fastest and most effectively (and use Google’s search engine as a tool of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was probably more disappointed than not when I first arrived, as it was a lot less extravagant than what I initially anticipated. However, I was able to solve more than I expected, which boosted my confidence in my general abilities as a “TECHY”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Competition" /><summary type="html">25 April</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/google.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Deloitte Start-Up Competition: SUITABLE</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/deloitte-startup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deloitte Start-Up Competition: SUITABLE" /><published>2019-04-19T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-19T12:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/deloitte-startup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/deloitte-startup/">&lt;p&gt;19 April&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/Deloitte-Powerpoint-FINAL.pptx&quot;&gt;Pitch Deck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuous 72 hours from project launch to final pitch to judges; the Deloitte Startup competition has just concluded, and there’s a fair amount to reflect on. The first thing to note is that mine and one other team easily did the most amount of work on our presentation, including the decking and presentation elements, yet neither of our teams placed on the top three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially this was a pretty rough disappointment, but I think there’s a lot that I learned from speaking to the judges afterwards. As lucrative our idea was, it was poorly communicated as my team got too focused on making our deck as concise and informative as possible, and going over the specific elements we were each going to say. Moreover, we weren’t all on the same page, because we tried to pivot the team (or at least I managed to), but we weren’t all present at every meeting. None of us really took charge of the project either, so there was no overall vision guiding us towards a proverbial “final destination”, which really showed in our work. The other team fell short where the judges noticed that it seemed like 3/5 of their members did all the work/talking, and as a result two of them didn’t manage to get the opportunity to say anything during their presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our idea was to have stations in areas trafficked highly by students and young professionals which would facilitate transactions between people who would rent professional outfits and people who would need a professional outfit in a pinch. It would bring convenience, ease of use, since it would save people the trouble of having to come already dressed, potentially long distances, and arrive sweaty and disheveled at interviews. However, we really weren’t able to drill in that last part, because initially our plan was simply to have exchanges take place where people would go to pick up outfits at other people’s homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also during the presentation we went over time, and I was in charge of financials, and I didn’t get a chance top prove my concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything’s a learning experience after all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Startup" /><category term="Product Management" /><summary type="html">19 April</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/deloittelogo.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CashMoney</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cashmoney/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CashMoney" /><published>2019-03-18T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-18T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cashmoney</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cashmoney/">&lt;p&gt;21 March&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go, starting to build some mental momentum, starting to build a list of things to do, I talked to Mark about this so let’s see where this takes us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CashMoney: “it’s Uber for tasks… for students”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did we get here? CashMoney is going to be my first attempt at creating my own startup. Pitching to the Convergent team was fun but I doubt that’s going to be of much value. I have to smooth out my wireframe for the Deloitte startup competition pitch too. I just can’t shake the feeling that I need more experience before going all in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial Pitch (Money Moves is a stupid name) &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1sUINtg3rSvm77jKlQES9pM_1cCDR3D0BmBC6wgd0Qrs/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Startup" /><category term="Product Management" /><summary type="html">21 March</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Berkeley Launch Accelerator - Compassionlit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compassionlit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Berkeley Launch Accelerator - Compassionlit" /><published>2019-03-17T09:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-17T09:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compassionlit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compassionlit/">&lt;p&gt;What a weekend. What a week. Nine days, two nights of sleep: I learned so much working with pharmaceutical device startup Compassionlit. Most entrepreneur stories are pretty amazing, but Nicolle was something else: she had an incredibly optimistic attitude no matter how much red tape she stumbled across. To meet someone who was working a regular occupation (nursing), recognized potential in their own idea and DROPPED THEIR ENTIRE LIFE to pursue it is truly something eye opening, and provides me a lot of perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compassionlit is a startup that produces phototherapy devices that help treat jaundiced newborns at 1% of the market price for comparable devices. They’re very small at the moment, and only just trying to get off their feed, but their website can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://box5653.temp.domains/~compauf8/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped Nicolle do market research for Ethiopia and Thailand, constructed a consumer journey to help her narrow down what kind of focuses she would need, and sketched out a go-to-market strategy for the Thailand market. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/compassionlit-consumerjourney.pptx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep depravation aside, I can’t wait to start pitching CashMoney.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Startup" /><summary type="html">What a weekend. What a week. Nine days, two nights of sleep: I learned so much working with pharmaceutical device startup Compassionlit. Most entrepreneur stories are pretty amazing, but Nicolle was something else: she had an incredibly optimistic attitude no matter how much red tape she stumbled across. To meet someone who was working a regular occupation (nursing), recognized potential in their own idea and DROPPED THEIR ENTIRE LIFE to pursue it is truly something eye opening, and provides me a lot of perspective.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/compassionlit.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Duff and Phelps Valuation Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/duff-and-phelps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Duff and Phelps Valuation Project" /><published>2018-10-20T22:35:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T22:35:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/duff-and-phelps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/duff-and-phelps/">&lt;p&gt;Duff &amp;amp; Phelps, an investment banking company, posted a case competition which challenged student teams to valuate a hypothetical public broadcasting company. Project specs can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/Duff_Phelps.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this was my first taste of financial work of any kind. Although I wasn’t able to finish every component of the deliverable, on account of entering the competition alone, I was able to learn a huge amount about the quantitative and qualitative elements behind business analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/Subscribers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Duff-Phelps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="Finance" /><summary type="html">Duff &amp;amp; Phelps, an investment banking company, posted a case competition which challenged student teams to valuate a hypothetical public broadcasting company. Project specs can be found here.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/Duff_Phelps.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Monkey Pod</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/monkeypod/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monkey Pod" /><published>2018-09-13T22:35:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-13T22:35:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/monkeypod</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/monkeypod/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/final3ddesign.png&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of E27 - Engineering Manufacturing, I was put into a team of five to develop a phone attachment which would provide “some functionality”. Project specs were scarce to encourage creativity, although looking back we probably went too far with our product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt; Our Product &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to design a “Monkey Pod”, a flexible tripod with claws that would bind to a phone in order for people to set up creatively positioned photos. It was inspired by the Gorillapod, which serviced cameras. I undertook the roles of Finance and Manufacturing lead for the project. The shear number of parts we needed to print out, as well as the perfection required, in terms of tolerance, to produce leg nodes that would both fit into each other and slide smoothly over each other, was overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/manufacturingstage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few sleepless nights of 3d printing later, we were able to proudly present our PLA plastic (incredibly difficult to make smooth) Monkey Pod, that could stand steadily across a multitude of diverse surfaces, and be equipped with a variety of phone types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/finalproduct.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Monkey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="Product Management" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/Duff_Phelps.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TEDx Talk: Judge Not</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/TEDx/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TEDx Talk: Judge Not" /><published>2017-01-11T17:23:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-11T17:23:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/TEDx</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/TEDx/">&lt;h1&gt; Judge Not &lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FPCdNpdZNKk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debate’s always been a part of my life: my parents were never the kind to just roll with my lofty claims or ideas as a child. From a very young age, my parents encouraged and drilled me to explore and analyze the “Why” behind every question I asked. As I developed my own personal values and ideologies, I found myself drifting towards determinism, an philosophical doctrine that, if taken consistently, I felt would promote the highest level of empathy for our fellow man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so excited to share my insights that I gave up the opportunity to organize TEDx in favour of having the opportunity to speak.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ethan-ding</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="TEDx" /><summary type="html">Judge Not</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ethan-ding.github.io/assets/images/TedX.jpg" /></entry></feed>